Roscoe H. Channing Collection 1907-1961
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Roscoe H. Channing Collection 1907-1961
MS 465
Channing, Roscoe H.
The bulk of this collection is from 1920-1950 and focuses on mining, both in Arizona and internationally. Most of the international material is from Hudson Bay Mining Company and their various mining operations in Canada. The collection also features personal papers that include confidential correspondence regarding the Labor movement in Canada. Arizona mining materials include information about the Miami Copper Company, Bagdad Mines and the San Manuel Mines.
3 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Roscoe H. Channing was born in New York City in 1868 and was the son of a prominent lawyer, also named Roscoe H. Channing and his wife, Susan. While he attended Princeton College, he was selected for the very first College All-American football team in 1889. After graduating in 1890, he immediately entered the mining field, becoming General Manager of Utah’s Consolidated Highland Boy Mine by 1897. When the Spanish-American War broke out, he resigned his position as General Manager and joined Teddy Roosevelt’s Rough Riders. In 1907 he became the President and General Manager of the Cerro de Pasco Copper Company mine in Peru. Eventually, Channing began managing much of the Whitney family mining businesses. This was followed by the establishment of the Hudson Bay Mining and Smelting Company, with his friend Cornelius Vanderbilt Whitney, with Channing serving as the President. He died in 1961.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 2 series
Mining, 1907-1958
Personal Papers, 1920-1961
Scope and Content Note
This collection has material on Arizona mining operations, International mining operations and the personal papers of Roscoe H. Channing. The Arizona materials consist of information regarding the Bagdad Mines, San Manuel Mines and the Miami Copper Company, with reports written by John Parke Channing, brother of Roscoe H. Channing and mining engineer. The International mining operations includes information about the Hudson Bay Mining and Smelting Company, in addition to various other operations in Peru and the Yukon. The Hudson Bay papers include correspondence, reports and financial statements.
Papers regarding the Labor Union in Canada include confidential correspondence about individual strikers, Labor Union leaders, and conversations with government officials regarding Labor Laws. There are also some photos of strikes and articles from various newspapers.
The personal papers of Roscoe H. Channing include some photographs, Rough Riders memorabilia, information regarding his house construction, legal papers, research files and Betsy Channing’s (wife of Roscoe H. Channing) personal notebook and correspondence.
Channing, Roscoe H.; Channing, John Parke, 1863-; Labor union members--Canada.; Copper mines and mining -- Arizona.; Mines and mineral resources--Arizona.; Mines and mineral resources--Canada.; Mines and mineral resources--Canada--History.; Copper mines and mining -- Arizona -- Bagdad -- History.; United States. Army. Volunteer Cavalry, 1st.; Flin Flon (Man.); San Manuel (Ariz.); photographs; maps; printed material
Container List
- Mining
  - Subseries 1: Arizona Mining
    - Bagdad Mines--Correspondence, Reports 1911-1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bagdad Mines, Maps, Charts 1907-1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Channing, J. Parke, Reports 1928 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Channing, J. Parke, Reports 1929 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - San Manuel Mines, Drilling Charts, Maps 1946 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - San Manuel Mines, Drilling Reports, Ore Estimates 1948 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - San Manuel Mines, Registration Statement 1933 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - San Manuel Mines, Reports 1929-1947 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - San Manuel Mines, Reports 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 2: International Mining
    - Hudson Bay, Annual Reports 1941-1958 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Hudson Bay, Correspondence, Austin, Eric 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Hudson Bay, Correspondence, B-L 1932-1957 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Hudson Bay, Correspondence, M-Z 1944-1956 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Hudson Bay, Financial Statements 1928-1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Hudson Bay, Printed Materials, Memos 1936-1957 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Hudson Bay, Reports 1926-1947 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Hudson Bay, Reports 1949 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Hudson Bay, Reports 1951-1954 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Hudson Bay, Reports 1956 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Hudson Bay, Reports 1957 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Mining Work, Channing, R.H. 1907-1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Mining Work, Channing, R.H. undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Mining Work, Notebooks undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Yukon Exploration 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 3: Labor Party Organizations and Protests
    - Articles and Publications 1931-1958 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, A-Z 1934-1956 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Photos undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Research 1934 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Series II: Personal Papers
  - Betsy Channing 1934-1961 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence- A-Z 1922-1959 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - House- Construction, Contracts 1937 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - House- Receipts, Correspondence, Estimates, Drafts 1936-1951 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Legal Documents 1931-1953 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Memorabilia, includes Rought Riders, College All-American football team, and various materials 1918-1950s (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Photos- Landscapes undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Photos- Outdoor Activities undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Photos- People undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Research Files 1915-1946 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Research Files 1947-1957 (Box 5, Folder 11)